We're talking about maps now.
It helps to know which way to go when you're out there.
This particular map is for the Appalachian Trail.
A lot of trails are marked with paint blazes.
They'll have like a little paint blaze, a little rectangle on each tree.
And you go to one, look for the next and go to the next.
But it's nice to have a map to kind of give you an idea what's off the trail.
Particularly handy if you need to do an evacuation and get out quick.
It's also handy in kind of setting yourself up mentally for what you're about to prepare.
A map's going to have a number of things.
It's going to have a legend that tells you what all the symbols are on the map.
It's going to have a scale to give you an idea of distance.
On the map it'll have like little lines.
Those are the contour lines, tells you the elevation of different parts.
Right here this has a really nice feature, a profile.
It gives you an idea of the elevation increases, judging that by mileage, and where on those you're going to find water, shelter and things like that.
So it helps to familiarize yourself with the map before you go out and know what you're going to get into.
If you have any questions give your local outfitter a holler.